Thomas Whalen

 • Maryland, United States
 ■ thomaswhalen1996@gmail.com
 □ 410-330-3334
 ■ in/thomas-a-whalen/
 • https://github.com/TmoWA

SUMMARY

I graduated from Western Governors University (WGU), earning a Bachelor of Science in Computer Science, and receiving multiple "excellence awards" for my coursework. I am also CompTIA Project+ certified and have experience working in a team.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science

Western Governors University · Salt Lake City, Utah · 2024

· Multiple machine learning, SQL, and Java courses.

CERTIFICATIONS

CompTIA Project+

CompTIA · 2023

· Covers industry-standard project management principles, with an emphasis on software projects.

SKILLS

Java, C++, SQL, Python, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, artificial intelligence, Jupyter Notebook, computer science, project management principles, problem solving, software design, employee training, student tutoring.

CODING PROJECTS

Sales Quantity Predictor

- Created using Python, Jupyter Notebooks, and Markdown. To view an online version of this project on Kaggle, click here or visit this URL: https://www.kaggle.com/code/thomas1421532234325/sales-predictor-demo.
- · Uses a random forest regressor machine-learning model to analyze a comma-separated values (CSV) file of automobile sales data, then predicts up to 12 months of future sales quantities.
- · Generates 3 graphs that communicate sales trends and visualize the machine-learning model's predictions.

Schedule Manager Application

- A Java program that communicates with an SQL database of saved employees and shifts, then uses that data to generate 3 employee schedules, all through a graphical user interface (GUI).
- · Includes support for changing table colors, editing data, and automatically adapting to the current date.
- · Sold to Cantler's Riverside Inn in 2020.

EXPERIENCE

Menu Designer (Remote)

Cantler's Riverside Inn

October 2021 - October 2023, Annapolis, Maryland

- Researched, designed, and developed multiple full-service dining and bar menus based on business trends. Each order contained 300 to 400 menus, depending on the restaurant's seasonal needs.
- $\cdot \ \text{Regularly led meetings with the management team of the restaurant to determine menu requirements and discuss design revisions.}$
- · Designed and delivered up to 5 new section charts (table layouts, table numbers, which table belongs to which section, etc.) per season.

Freelancing and Self-Study

Freelance

March 2020 - November 2022, Annapolis, Maryland

- · Completed hundreds of hours of self-study.
- Finished 11 personal projects, including a color histogram analyzer, a tic-tac-toe bot, and an SQL-backed employee management and daily task tracker for use with the schedule manager mentioned in the "Coding Projects" section.
- Developed and sold a schedule management application to "Cantler's Riverside Inn." The application enabled the automated generation of charts for hourly worker shifts, reportedly saving 5 hours per week and increasing profitability by 23% for the management team.

Various Positions

Cantler's Riverside Inn

July 2012 - March 2020, Annapolis, Maryland

- · Prepared food while adhering to regulatory safety and sanitation requirements as an expediter.
- Trained 14 new employees for various positions as an expediter, cleaner, and server.
- · Supervised 4 kitchen cooks and functioned as a liaison between the kitchen and front-of-house staff.